Adedamola Adesina Adeagbo

Federal Capital Territory, NG
 □ damoladeagbo@gmail.com □ +234(808)-232-3270

in Adedamola A. Adeagbo & Portfolio

PROFILE

Experienced Data Analyst and Brand Strategist with 3 years of experience. Increased marketing ROI by 20% and brand awareness by 200% in 1 year. Developed automated report system, improving efficiency by 20% in 2 years. Enhanced strategy effectiveness by 25% in 14 months.

SKILLS

- Tableau & Power BI Visualization
- Data Modelling
- Database Management Systems (DBMS)
- SQL (Microsoft SQL, MySQL)
- Dashboard Design & Development
- Critical Thinking
 & Problem Solving
- Python Programming
- Data Analysis & Interpretation
- Branding & Business Strategy
- Statistical Knowledge
- Microsoft Suite (Excel, Powerpoint)
- Digital Marketing

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

April 2022 – present Lagos, Nigeria

Business Intelligence Analyst (Marketing)

49thStreet Media Agency

- Led primary and secondary research on digital marketing, ads marketing, and brand promotions resulting in a 20% increase in marketing ROI.
- Utilized Power BI and SQL for data extraction, ETL processes, and data modeling to provide strategic insights for stakeholder decision-making.
- Optimized strategies through data-driven adjustments with social media analytics tools, boosting effectiveness by 25%.
- Promoted cross-departmental collaboration between marketing and content creation teams to enhance impact and drive brand success.
- Prepared concise reports and presentations for business meetings, increasing opportunities by 15% and boosting strategy effectiveness by 25%.
- Contributed to the development of a report generation system using GA4 Analytics & SQL, improving brand structure and operations.
- Monitored social media metrics with Mailchimp & Google Analytics to refine the social media strategy based on mentions, trends, and impressions.

March 2023 – February 2024 Ontario, Canada

Data Analyst (Sales)

Insurance Supermarket Inc

- Utilized customer demographics and insurance plans to shape campaign strategy, leading to a 20% increase in lead generation.
- Improved Sales team's forecasting accuracy by 6% using advanced analytical methods
- Implemented SQL-based data quality checks, boosting data accuracy by 10% and reducing reporting errors.
- Created and managed Tableau dashboards for displaying key business metrics, enhancing decision-making efficiency by 30%.

- Collaborated with marketing and sales teams to translate business objectives into specific data needs for targeted ad campaigns.
- Conducted training sessions on Tableau usage, enhancing team productivity and data visualization skills.

January 2022 – February 2023 Ontario, Canada

Brand Strategist & Social Media Analyst

Draft.co

- Increased social media content by 15%, boosting brand visibility.
- Utilized competitor analysis to identify and leverage 15% more opportunities, enhancing market position.
- Improved strategy effectiveness by 25% with data-driven adjustments using Twitter and Instagram analytics tools, leading to increased brand performance.
- Achieved a 200% rise in brand awareness within one year.
- Created dashboards and reports to communicate research findings clearly to clients and internal stakeholders.

PROJECTS

June 2024

Exploring Sales Insights and Trends at Clothing Company 🗷

- Utilized **MySQL** for data cleaning, ETL process and data exploration, to improve data quality and generate data-driven insights and patterns.
- Visualized the results of the analysis into multiple dashboards using Power BI to present to key stakeholders.
- Provided technical insights on how the client can fully utilize their data to determine where stronger marketing actions are required.

May 2024

Data Cleaning and Exploratory Analysis of a Global Electronics Retailer \square

- Using MySQL to implement and Extract, Transform and Load (ETL) Process to
 pull data from the different platforms and consolidate it into a single
 database.
- Performed data cleaning using **MySQL** to improve data quality and exploratory analysis to generate data-driven insights.
- Created a dashboard on **Power BI** for data visualization and validation of generated results from SQL queries to present to stakeholders.

April 2024

Sales & Marketing Data for Pharmaceutical Company 🛭

Virtual Client's Project

- Utilized MySQL to extract data from 6 different related tables from customer sales databases using JOIN and VIEW.
- Transformed and filtered data by using aggregating and filtering function to improve reporting process.
- Performed data cleaning and data manipulation using power query on Excel to ensure data validity.
- Created a dashboard on Tableau for data visualization and to present actionable insights from the data.

March 2024

Customer Churn Rate Analysis 🛮

Personal Project

- Transformed and processed client's data by using Power Query and Excel to ensure data completeness and validity.
- Created a dashboard with Tableau to help client compare between the churn rate, customer retention rate and customers who joined.
- Provided technical insights on how the client can fully utilize their data to determine where stronger marketing actions are required.

January 2024

Market Analysis & Insights on US Coffee Market

Personal Project

- Transformed and filtered data by using aggregating and filtering function to improve reporting process
- Established a foundation for a data-driven decision-making approach, leading to more effective strategies and stronger business outcomes.
- Created interactive dashboards in Tableau to visually represent the data and make the findings more comprehensible.

EDUCATION

March 2014 – June 2019

B.Sc. Mechanical Engineering

Obafemi Awolowo University, Ile-Ife, Osun, Nigeria.

CERTIFICATES

• Microsoft Power BI Developer (2024)

• Tableau Certified Developer (2023)

• Certified Data Analyst - IBM (2022)

• SEO Fundamentals - Google (2022)

FURTHER EDUCATION (COURSES)

May 2024 SQL for Data Science ☑

University of California

November 2023 Python for Data Science, AI & Development

IBM

June 2021 Marketing Analytics 🖸

University of Virginia

October 2020 Brand Management: Aligning Business, Brand and Behaviour

University of London

May 2020 Google SEO Fundamentals ♂

University of California, Davis

April 2020 Project Manager

International Project Management Association